yeah so that's how we display player
life
and next we create an event class
so let's create a
new class
inside of this main package let's create
a new class
and i'm gonna name this event
handra
this graph also use game panel
gp
and constructor
public
event
tundra
game
panel jp
this
gp
equal gp
alright and i'll go to this game
panel and instantiate this class
so
somewhere around here
a public
event
hundred
e
and passing this
i think there are several ways to
trigger event
and this time we handle it by creating
another rectangle
next tango
i'm gonna name this event
predict and also we
set this
event like
default x and y
and instantiate it in the constructor
so
event
select
equal new
rectangle
and okay so event
left dot x
so
you can choose any size but i choose a
very small size for this so it will be
two pixels by two pixels rectangle
and place it at the center of the tile
so the parameter
will be something like this
x equal 23
select that y equal 23
with
equal to
height call 2
and also set the default
dot y
and
this
yeah like this
the reason i chose it small like this
is for example if the rectangle is as
large as a tile size the event gets
triggered when player's solid area hits
the
edge of the tile like somewhere around
here but i personally want the event
gets triggered when player moves a bit
further into the tile
like this
that's why i set the trigger point at
the middle of the tile
and next we create our method
public void
check
event
and create another method
public
boolean not available
string
and
click
direction required direction
and okay so volume
hit
first
and return
hit
so this is the method that checks event
collision and it works pretty similar to
object collision
let me type first gp.player.solid
area dot x equals
dot x
copy and paste
y
and y
and then we get event rectangles
position two
event
select dot x equal
call
times repeater
type size
plus
event
select
x
so basically this means this event
rectangles world x
and okay so
copy and paste
y
and this time this is
love
and the y
and then we use uh intersex method again
and check if player is colliding this
event rectangle so if
gp dot player dot so read
area
dot
intersects
event
left
them
if
gp.player
that
direction
that equals
like
direction
and or
like
direction that equals
any
then
hit
equal true
so if collision is happening this
returns true
and the difference is we check the
player's direction
this time
so you can choose either
event happens only when player is facing
a certain direction or
it happens regardless
and finally we reset the player and
event rectangles x and y
gp dot
player dot
solid
area dot x
equal gp dot gp.player dot solid
area default x
solid area dot y
equal gp dot player dot
solid area default y
and also event
select dot x
call
and
select
default x
and select dot y
equal event
left
default y
yeah so as i said the mechanics is
almost identical to the object collision
so now
we have this heat method
we can pass
these parameters from here
so
let's create a sample event which
decreases player's life
i'm gonna create a path around here
time
okay
and here i'm gonna place a damage pit
so if player hit this tile then he
receives damage
so it's a column 27 and lao 16
so we type like this
if
hit
[Music]
and
right
equal
true
then
event
happens
we use this hit method as a condition of
this boolean if statement
so we pass column and log
and
require the direction
and if it returns true
then the event happens we can type the
result here but then this method will be
very long as we add more events so let's
handle it in a separate method
damage
pit
public void damage
it
and we receive one parameter here
game state
gp dot game state equal gain state
then create whatever the result of this
event
gp dot ui dot
current
dialog
we're going to display a text
you fall into up pit
and we're gonna decrease
player life
life
like -1
and since we want to display
this text so we're going to pass
dialogue state here
let me change the format i think i like
this
format better
okay so this event is done
so let's call this check event method
from the player graph
so go to player and
after this npc collision
check
event
and gp dot
e
hundred
dot
check event
and uh okay let me disable this
so start from the maximum life
okay
let's go
yeah you fall into a pit you lose one
life
yeah
like this
this is working fine but just giving him
damage is a bit harsh so let's create a
healing event too
and this time we set an event so if you
press enter key in front of this water
pool
you can recover your life
so the event gets triggered only when
you press enter key while you are
touching the event rectangle so first
create another event method
public void
hearing
pool
or something
and get game state
and this time we add one condition
if
key h dot enter pressed
equal to
then gp.game
state
and okay some direct text message
current dialogue
called you drink
the water
and
lime break
your
life has been
recovered
and
player live
equal
player dot max
live
gp dot key h dot enter
rest
equal
false
and finally we check this event
if
hit
column 23 and
row 12
and the direction is up
equal to
then
we call that the healing pool
and the past
dialogue state
here
like this okay
so let's
check okay first let's uh
fall into the pit
let's see damage receive damage receive
damage okay
let's drink the water so i'm gonna press
enter
oops
nothing happens why
what
wait
hmm this is weird
what
why
okay
i found out
the reason
so this is the reason
sorry this is my mistake so if we are
not touching any any pc then uh
this automatically
changes enterprise too far
so
i think we shouldn't put this here
and okay
and i think we should do it after
everything was done so somewhere around
here after we check npc and
event then we can change this to first
so
we
yeah this one this line tools this
shouldn't be here yeah sorry about that
so forget about this so you can delete
this
so we handle that line
for here
yeah so
now this should work
all right
okay
repeat and press enter
okay so you drink the water your life
has been recovered
okay
yeah working good
so we have succeeded to implement two
events
and this time we only changed the player
life but basically you can trigger any
event for example when you hit a certain
tile you can teleport to other location
or stuff like that
[Music]
and i haven't decided what we will do
next but
probably it's about time to fight some
monsters
since you know player has life now
anyway that's it for now thanks for
watching and until next time
[Music]