hi guys this is roy snow so
after finishing our first game i
uploaded some sort of modification
videos such as improving rendering speed
and pixel art but from this video we
actually resume the development and
starts the second half
as i said in the very first video of
this series
we will turn this into an action rpg
so no simple key finding demonstration
game anymore
and here's a bit more detailed load map
of the second half
we set game state so we can handle
various situations in the game we create
an npc and dialog system so we can talk
to them
we create more detailed player stats
such as player life level attack defense
experience stuff like that
we create monsters and
implement a simple ai
so they spawn on the map and move around
and we implement a battle system so
player can attack and receive damage
then we implement inventory so we are
not just adding plus one to integer
variable
but
handle this in more
object oriented way this will be a bit
tricky one but i will explain step by
step
and
we also add them merchant npc so we can
buy and sell items with them
and uh we create title screen and game
over screen
we handle this by switching game state
and uh we also implement a little
interaction with environment
not gonna go too deep into this area but
a twist will be able to cut trees with
an axe
and there's some more
and besides this i might add other stuff
if i come up with some ideas or receive
some ideas through comments
so
in any case feel free to leave a comment
whenever you don't understand something
or
you have some features to implement
anything is fine
okay
in this first episode of the second half
we
implement
gamestate and
as a part of this game state we
implement a pause screen so we can pause
the game and while implementing this we
also do a little housekeeping and delete
stuff that we don't use anymore
so let's start
okay so first we create some integers
this is
game
statement and public hint
game state
and also public
final in
a play state equal one
and public final int
power power state
equal to
so
what is game state
when you play a game
usually it has various game situations
such as title screen
the main gameplay screen
or
in game menu screen
stuff like that
and depending on the situation
the program draws different things on
the screen
and often receive different
key input
for example
you can swing your sword by pressing
enter in gameplay state
but maybe enter works as confirmation
key in many screen
so we handle this by telling our program
what kind of game state we are in right
now
so i just put one to this play state and
the two to
this pulse state but basically you can
choose any number
and for now we start the game with this
play state
so
in this setup game
we set the default game state
game state
equal play state
you know uh technically you don't really
need to create these
and uh
so typing like
like these
but uh
the reason i didn't do that is because
um
maybe you want to switch these numbers
later
maybe i want to use 0 for pause state
and uh yeah 2 for play state or
something and 1 for title screen or
something like that
if you are
putting numbers like this manually then
uh
when you change
this you know kind of allocation then
you will track everything and change
this number one two three or something
like that
but if you have set
individual state like this then you only
need to change you know this number like
this then uh
then this automatically adjusts the
change
so as always fine but uh
this time we're gonna set each game
state like this
okay
and then
and then go to update
method here
and we create an if statement like this
if
gamestate
equal one no not one
uh play
state
then we're gonna call display a dot
update
and if
game state
recall pause state
then
nothing for now
what this means is we don't update the
player information while the game is
paused so we cannot move our sprite
okay then go to this keyhandra
and create a shortcut for
pausing the game
but first we create a constructor and
receive game panel because we need it
this dot gp
then
accept a key input
copy and paste
and i'm going to use
p key
for pause but you can choose whatever
key you want
and if
gp dot
game state
equal gp dot
play state
then we're gonna change this to power
state so game state
state
and uh else if
gp.gamestate
equal gp dot
pause state
gp dot games
state
gold gb dot play state
yeah like this
and then go to
this ui class
and we'll do a little housekeeping here
since uh
most of the stuff here is for our
previous treasure hunting game so we're
not gonna use anymore
so first delete this one
and this one
we're not gonna display the key image or
key number on the screen anymore
and uh okay and inside with straw method
basically
we we're gonna delete everything
and yeah everything
okay then inside of this ui class first
we're gonna declare
this graphic study
and inside of this draw method
this
g2
equal g2
we do this so we can use this g2 in
other methods in this class
okay then we set a
default font
so g2 dot set font
so okay for now let's use this area 40
and the g2 dot set
color
correct
white
and here we check the current game state
if
gp dot
game state
equal
gp dot play state
then
to
play state
stuff
later
and
gp dot
game state
call gp dot
parts
state
maybe you can
maybe we can use switch
for this
but yeah if statement is okay too i
think
and so we're gonna type
what we're gonna do or draw during this
play state and
pause state and technically we can type
everything here
but then this draw method will be really
long
and huge
and kind of hard to track what is
happening
so we will handle situations by
splitting them to methods
so
first we create
method called
draw
powers
screen
and we gonna call this from here
so
we're gonna do all the pause screen
stuff in this method
okay first
string
text
equal
paused
and also we're gonna create x and
y
and uh
finally d2 dot draw
string
text and x and y so we want to display
this
at the
center of the screen
and finding this y is kind of easy you
just need to type like this gp dot
square
height
divided by 2
and for this x
it's basically the same as
congratulations text that we displayed
in a
previous game so
it's gonna be like this
pink links
g2 dot
get
text
context is g2
and
get
width
and x
equal
gp dot
screen
reads
divided by 2
minus
length divided by two
so this way we can display the text at
the center of the screen
but we will likely do this calculation
again and again throughout the
development and typing this
every time
is kind of too much pain so
let's handle this with a method
public hint
and get x
for
centered
text or something like that
and we get string
and text
and basically we gonna
cut down the copy here
yeah
so
index
and we're gonna return this x
so
now we only need to call this
get x4 center text and pass this text
so this way whenever we want to get the
x for
centered text
we just need to call
this method
okay this ui class is done for now
and now we'll do another housekeeping so
go to playerclass
and delete
this one
husky
so we don't use this anymore
and also
inside of this pickup object method
we're gonna delete everything
but this if statement
yeah
and then go to this
asset setup
and
so since these are all for
the treasure hunting game so
delete everything
and inside of this game panel let's pass
this game panel to the constructor of
keyhandra
okay i think that's everything
so let's check the program
okay i'm gonna press p key
maybe i want to make the text a bit
larger
so
yeah here so g2
set font
g2 dot
get font
derive font
maybe
right now it's 40 so
like 80.
okay yeah looks good
so now we can pause the game
so even if i press
wsd keys
the character doesn't respond while game
is paused
alright i think that's it for now
and in the next video we will implement
an npc and maybe direct system as well
thanks for watching and until next time
[Music]