hi guys this is roy snow
last time we implemented an npg
so now we are no longer alone in this
world
and in this video we will implement a
dialogue system so
we can talk to him okay first inside of
this game panel
so we're gonna set a new game state
public final int
dialog
state
three
and then
open this ui graph
let's delete this and
this
i think we are not using this
anymore
i'm gonna delete this too
all right and in this
draw method
we add another if statement
this is
place date
and part
state
and now we create a
dialog
state
if
gp dot game state equal gp dot
dialog state
so if the game state is dialog we call a
method and do some direct stuff
like
draw
dialogue
screen
i think
and we create this
method public void
draw
dialogue
okay first we create a
dialog window so
window
now we want to display a dialog window
somewhere around here
and uh so what we're gonna do is
basically
drawing a big rectangle here
so
first we set some parameters for the
window
into x
and y
in
with
print
height
and okay so for the x
so it's somewhere around here
gp dot tiles
size times two
so two tiles to the right from the
left edge
and for y
is
one tile or maybe half tile to the
bottom
called gp dot tile
size
divided by two
so and this is
screen
so we subtract
so
four tiles
from the screen with
size
times four
and the height is gp dot type
size
i don't know five tiles
height
so
i just write calculating
tile base like this but uh you know
if you want you can type
number here like this this is also fine
so with these parameters
we create a kind of a mini window or sub
window and i think we gonna do it in a
separated method since we will likely
create this kind of window a lot so
like
public void
draw
a sub window or something
and this method
receive
x
y
with
and
height
so yeah basically we're gonna pass
everything
to this method
x y
with
height
okay
first we set the color of this sub
window
and i choose block
but this time
so usually we type like this
right
but this time we don't use this
default java color but instead we create
a
new color by typing rgb numbers
so like this
color
she
equal new
color
and
so since it's a black color so 0
and we're gonna set this
c
on this graphics 2d
okay and now with this color we draw a
rectangle
right g2
fill
round
left
so this time we use this
round direct
and when you draw this round rectangle
the graphics 2d asks you to fill these
parameters
so x y with height the usual stuff and
also
aqueous and arc height
so we can you know
change the roundness of this round
rectangle
and this time i'm gonna type
35 and the solidify but you can adjust
you know these numbers as you like
all right and now go to this player
class
and
inside of this
interrupt npc
we don't use this anymore
so if the index is not
that means player is touching on any pc
so
we can change the game state here
gp dot game state
equal gp dot dialog state
so with this
when the
when the program draws this ui stuff
it calls this draw dialogue screen
method
okay let's check this
yeah
so i think
i want to reduce the height a little bit
because
you know
so
yeah
so when the npc is above you then uh
this box basically hides him so this is
not so good so uh
i'm gonna reduce the
height of this sub window
to
four tiles
yep this is better
so when you touch on any pc this sub
window shows up
but i think this
window
still looks kind of too generic
you know i think it would look better if
it had a
white frame around it
so
yeah let's go back to this draw
subwindow method
and this time
we set
white color
she called new
color
and white is to
255 and 255
this is the rgb number for white
and then so to draw the frame
we set the
stroke
stroke and then
new basic
basic
stroke
and here we type the
width of this stroke
and i choose 5 pixels
and with this we draw
another round rectangle
to do that
but this time
so not feel round wrecked but just
draw round left
and the parameter is
x
plus five
y plus five
and which is
minus 10
height is also
minus 10 and the arc
is like 25 25
okay let's check
oops
why
oh yeah of course i forgot to set the
color
g2.set
all right
yeah
i like this better
so this looks fine
but we can add a little more touch to
make this even cooler
so when we set this rgb numbers we can
actually add one more number
like this
so this
fourth number is called alpha value so
basically it indicates its transparency
or opacity level
so if it's 255
there's no transparency i'll show you
with some examples
yeah so with 255 there is no difference
but if it's
so you see the difference
so we can see the background
and if it's like
so the transparency increases
and if it's zero
nothing it's completely transparent
so by adjusting this alpha value
you can change the object's opacity
level
so for this black rectangle i set
like 210
yeah so
you can somehow see the background
but the window is still kind of dark so
it's good for displaying text on it
now let's display some text
okay inside of this ui class first we
create a
string
public
current
dial
block
okay then inside of uh
entity
create a string alley
string
dialogues
call new string
size is like 20
okay then
go to this old main graph
and we create a method
public void
and set
dialog
yes
and here we can store some dialogue text
for this character
so for example like
hello lot
so
each character can have this dialog
array
and you can put text in it i set the
length of this alley 20 but if you want
to add more dialogues you can change the
ranks and
you can also replace the text
inside of this array along the gameplay
then
we call this method
from this constructor
then we create another method
so
somewhere around here
public
void
i'm gonna name this speak
we create this speak method both in the
subclass and also in this entity
superclass 2
speak
ok now go to the player class
and we call that speak method so
gp dot
npc
index i
dot speak
all right and okay return to this old
man
gp dot ui
dot current dialog
equal
dialog
zero for now
so we get a text from this alley
and pass it to this current dialog
string in this ui class
so now we can display this text
in this ui class
okay so inside of this
this draw dialog screen
first we decide where to display the
text
so the text should be inside of this sub
window so like
plus gp dot tile size so we just
oops
gp dot tile
size
and y
plus
gp dot tile size
then we draw the text
so g2 dot
draw
string
and the current
dialog
and x and y
yeah let's check
okay
the font is a bit large i think so
let's change the size
dot
get font
the live font
font dot playing
so right now it's
40 i think
yeah so
sorry to
yep looks better
then now let's add more dialogues to
this npc
one two three
one
two
three
and okay so the second one is
so you
come to
this
island
to
find the treasure
or something yeah
now we adjust our code a little bit so
these texts can be displayed one by one
in the entity class
first we create an integer
dialog
index
and then in this old main class
so we change this 0 to
dialog
index
and after passing the dialog
we increase this index
so this way
you know next time we call this speak
method then
this passes the
next dialogue
okay
so
oh and yeah
we need to
close the window
right now it's not responding anything
so
okay so open kihenra
okay
i think first we better check the
current game state
if gp dot
game state
call gp dot play state
then we can basically
move everything
so this is
play
state
and okay so
pause state
and also
dialog
state
here
gp dot
game state
equal gp dot pod state
if gp dot game state
call gp dot
dialog state
so if game state is play state and if
you press p then uh
game state changes to this pause state
let's delete this
yeah and okay let's copy this and
so if
game state is pause state and uh
if you press p then the game state will
change back to play state yeah so now
this
direct state ah and also this should be
earth i think
so if we are in the dialogue state and
if
we press
like
enter key
for example
enter
then
we finish the dialogue state so
gamestate
equal
gp.playstate
not player
state
okay
check
all right
and uh so press enter
yeah and talk again
so the second dialogue is displayed and
the text is bleeding out of the frame
but don't worry about it we'll fix it
soon
and on
next text
hmm
uh
yeah now we got uh null pointer
exception error
because there is no text
in the array index 4 so let's take care
of this first
we had an if statement here
if
dialogues
die
log
index
equal null
then
dialog
index
equals zero
so if there is no text we go back to
index zero
hello lot
yeah just second text
the third one
force
and the first one again
so now error is gone
but
i think it would be better if
the npc
turns themselves to us when we talk to
them
yeah you know this is like we are
talking to his back
so
inside of this
speak method
we create a
switch or if statement
and the condition is
player's
direction
the case
up
so if players direction is up then uh
we're gonna change this npc's direction
to down
left
okay let's check
right
yeah hello let
yup
so this looks more natural i think
and uh
i want to add a little more touch
or more like
provide an option to you guys
right now this dialog window opens up
automatically when you hit the npc
but maybe some of you guys want to open
it only when you hit the key
so i actually like that better
so
let's go to this key handler
first
we're gonna add another volume
and tap
rest
and while
we are in display state
so we're gonna add this entire
input
so
we can
enter
if we press enter then
list
equal true
and go to
the player class
we check if
gp.key
h
oh okay i think we need to
change this to public
and kh dot end top rest so if
we check if
enterprise is
true or not
okay so if it's true then
we do this
and make sure to set this files
after checking this
otherwise you know this will be
true for good
yeah let's check
all right so now
dialogue doesn't open up
but if you press enter
yeah so you can talk to this npc
so the now window opens only
when you press enter key while any pc
collision is happening
and finally it's time to take care of
the
line break
so we want to break the line at some
point so we're gonna insert
backslash n
boxer chain
but this is not enough
if we are displaying text on a component
such as j text area or j label
the line automatically breaks at this
back search end
but unfortunately
the graphics to these draw method
completely ignore these signs
show you
yeah like this so nothing changes
so
we need to do a little more adjustment
okay so
inside of this ui graph
we type like this
for
string
line
current
die
log
dot
split
and
yeah box russian
and okay let's copy
instead of this current dialogue
type lime
and after that we
increases this y
like 40
so
what we are doing here is we split the
text that is inside of this dialog
at this keyword
and get it as this
line
so basically you can use any symbol
the line breaks up
whatever you typed between these double
quotations
and after displaying a line
we increase the y
so the next line will be displayed below
the first line
yeah so let's check
hello that
yeah so you've come to this island to
find the treasure
um okay
maybe font is still a bit too large
okay i think i'm gonna decrease the size
size a little bit
looks better much better
so now the text is divided into multiple
lines and displayed nicely
let's go back to this old main class
and maybe you have noticed but
you know these lines
can be shared by other npcs too
so actually
we can move this
to
this entity class
and
we just call the method from here
super dot speak
then you know
it works
exactly like before
so we don't need to type this every time
we create a new character
then
maybe you think then what's the point of
creating this speak method here in in
its subclass
yeah so the program works without
without these
but
i created this because
maybe we want to add some character
specific stuff later
for example if you have some kind of a
special item then uh
he speaks something different
or yeah like that
so
leaving this method here makes such you
know customization easier yeah
do this
character specific
stuff
all right so
this is the basic system for displaying
dialogues
and now let's talk about the
font in this game
[Music]
you