hi guys this is roy snow
last time we created the title screen
so now we have this simple looking title
screen
and in this video we will implement
player life let's start
i have created these heart sprites
so there are three images
so blank heart and
through heart and half heart
so i'm gonna copy these images to
[Music]
okay
this object package
okay then we create another
object graph
so
another class
and i'm gonna name this obj
heart
and this graph also extends
the object
and okay i think we can borrow
the format from as object graph
so let's copy and
paste
and change the name
heart
and okay so here so unlike
other objects this heart class has three
images so blank half and full
so let's open this super object
and add two more buffered image here so
image two and the image three
note
image
image2
so now we can read three images here
so uh
copy and paste
and image two image three
and okay so first one is
hot
and the second one is hot
half
and hot
wrong
and then we're gonna scale them so
image two and the image
three okay so yeah this class is done
for now
now go to the entity class
and
add two integer variables
kerala
first one is
max life
and
life
these two integers will be shared by
player and monsters
ok then open
the player class
and
we set players life value
probably here inside of this set default
values
layer
state of
so first max drive
so you can choose any number here
basically
and
i'm gonna choose six
and life
equal so default is max life
so this will be players current life
and in this game
one life means half heart and the two
lives mean full heart
so six lives mean
three hearts it might be a bit confusing
at first
but please remember this basic concept
so two lives equals one heart
okay now go to the
ui class
and here we will display player life on
the screen
so first we need those hard images so we
prepare
buffered images for that
upward image
heart
full
half
heart
blank
then we get
these images
somewhere around here
create
hud
object
super object
part
equal new obj
heart
and past gp
okay and first heart
who
we call heart dot
image
heart
half
a goal
heart dot image 2
heart
lung
image 3
like this
and next we draw these hard images on
the screen so
ok
so inside of this play state
we call a method
so draw
a player life or something
and i'm gonna add this method
in this polled state and this dialog
state too
so player life still displayed in these
screens but it's up to you if you want
to hide player life during the game is
paused then
you don't need to add this one
and we create this method
so public void draw
player
life
and first we decide where to display the
heart image
and i want to display somewhere around
here
so
first fix call
gp dot type
size
like half
half tile
and
why it's also half tile
this is the starting point
so i mean we are drawing multiple hearts
so if players max life is six we draw
three hearts
and
we handle this drawing by creating a
while loop
so first we create an integer into i
start from zero
then we create a while loop
while
i
is the sum gp dot player dot max
life
divided by 2
then
g2 dot draw
image
heart
blank
x
white no
then
i plus plus
and also
we increase
the x
by
type
size
like this
so first we draw the blank heart image
so according to the players current max
drive
so yeah remember two lives mean one
heart so that's why we divide this max
life by two
and after drawing a heart
we increases to i and x by tile size
so the next image will be displayed
on the right
yeah so let's check this
oops
wow it's so small
why maybe something went wrong in
skating
ah yeah okay
um
we needed to get the scaled image
yeah sorry about that this is
this was my mistake so
now it should work
check again
yeah okay
hmm so three blank hot images are now
displayed so basically we have displayed
the player's max life here
and now we will display the player's
current life
draw
blank
part
okay first let's reset these values
so
reset
draw
current
life okay let me change this draw
marks life
now we draw not blank heart but
half heart or full heart images
so while
i
gp.player
dot live
so this time the ranks is set by not max
life but the current player life g2 dot
draw
image
heart
half
and x white
no
so
if this i
is less than the current player life
first we draw a half heart
then
increase this i
then we check again
if
i is less than
dp.player.life
then this time we draw
hot
so if this increased i
is still less than the current player
life
we draw a
full heart
and after that we increase this eye
again
and
also increase this x
tile size
oops
size
so if this condition is matched
basically we
replace this half heart
with this full heart
and after that we
go to the next heart
yeah that's how it works so let's check
okay so now
three full hearts are displayed because
player is currently at his max life
but if we change the player's current
life
okay so
player
life
equal
then
so player has only one two three four
five lives
if it's two
like this
yeah so that's how we display player
life
and next we create an
event class
and implement some sample events so we
can give some damage to player
and also
recover his life
[Music]
you