hi guys, this is RyiSnow
from this video, I will start a 2D game tutorial in Java
this is something I've been wanting to do for quite a while
so I'm happy that I can finally start this
compared to other game tutorials that I have done before,
such as the text-based adventure game,
2D game development is a bit more complicated
and requires a bit more work
so I will do my best to make this as easy as possible
so you can follow the steps even if you have no experience in developing 2D games
so I'm very happy if you enjoy it
for this one, we will not use any external libraries
we will just use the default Java classes and make it from the scratch
so if you have an environment to write Java code,
you can make this game
and here's the roadmap of this tutorial
first, we make a relatively simple treasure hunting game
by creating this, you can learn how to create a game loop
which is the core of 2D game development
and also (you can learn) how to display characters, background tiles,
item objects on the screen
and you can also learn how to move player character on the screen
and after completing this first game,
we will add more elements to this and change it to a 2D action RPG,
kind of like the retro-style Zelda
we will add monsters, NPCs, dialogues,
inventory, some events
that's the final goal of this tutorial
this is a tutorial for Java 2D beginners so I will explain many things
such as how the game loop works, etc.
so if you already have some knowledge of 2D game programming
you probably feel the pacing is a bit slow
but please bear with me everyone is beginner at first
and someone else might find these explanations useful
okay, so that's the introduction
and now let's start the development
let's make a new project
I'm gonna name this My2DGame
that's the most generic name ever but it's okay
and don't create this
and let's create a package first
and name this "main"
and create a class
let's create Main class
so first we create a window
so we use this JFrame class
so we can close this window properly
and also we add...
so we cannot resize this window
then let's set the game title
so... "2D adventure" or something
so window is gonna be displayed at the center of the screen
so we can see this window
okay now let's create another class
and I'm gonna name this GamePanel
and this GamePanel extends JPanel
so basically this is a subclass of this JPanel
so this has all the functions of this JPanel
this GamePanel works as a kind of a game screen
so first we're gonna decide some screen settings
and create some variables here
and I'm going to choose 16
so this means 16 by 16 tile
and this 16 by 16 is gonna be the default size of the player character,
NPCs and map tiles in this game
16 by 16 is kind of a standard size for many retro 2D games
and many characters and tiles are made with this size
so you can find many examples
some games use more pixels such as 32 by 32 to draw a character
but we go with 16 pixels this time
that said there is a little catch here
since modern computers and monitors have much higher resolutions
than those eras of NES or SNES, you know, 80s, 90s
so 16 by 16 characters or tiles look very small on the screen
for example, the NES's resolution was 256 by 224
and the GENESIS was 320 by 224
so 16 by 16 characters looked a decent size in those settings
but I'm sure your monitor has much higher resolution than that
then what to do?
we will scale it
so let's create an integer variable
and I'm going to set 3
although we create characters in a 16 by 16 frame
but it looks 48 by 48 pixels on the screen
this kind of scaling is pretty common for developing retro style 2D games
so we also follow the tradition
so another integer
so basically this is 48 x 48 tile
so this is the actual tile size that will be displayed on our game screen
and then we decide the size of our game screen
and to do that we first decide how many tiles the game can display
both horizontally and vertically
and this will decide the total screen size
in this game we choose 16 column
and row is 12
16 tiles horizontally, 12 tiles vertically
so the ratio is 4 to 3
and since a single tile size is 48 pixels...
so tile size is 48
and the height is...
so this will be the size of our game screen
but of course you can change it if you want
18 or 14 or something
then this screen width the screen height will change automatically
so that's the screen setting
now let's create a constructor of this GamePanel
so we're gonna set the panel size of this GamePanel
so screen width and screen height
and then I'm not sure if this is necessary but...
let's set the background color of this GamePanel
if you have experience developing 2D games in Java before
and if you have used Canvas to draw the screen
then you probably used BufferStrategy too
but this time we're gonna use this JPanel
this JPanel has kind of a double buffering function as default
so I think it's a good idea to make this true for better rendering performance
okay now let's go back to this Main class
and add this GamePanel to this window
and we're gonna add this gamePanel to this window
this is a subclass of JPanel
so basically this is a JPanel class with a bit more extra functions
so you can add this to window like you add JPanel to this window
and then we're gonna pack this JPanel so we can see it
okay let's check it
alright so our game screen appears
and the size is 768 and 576
so we can display a 16 48x48 tiles horizontally
and 12 48x48 tiles vertically
now we have a window
so let's talk about the basic mechanics of the game
I think the most important concept of 2D games is
"the existence of time"
in my previous text adventure game,
when you do something, for example, press the button
then program do some processing and then stops
it just waits until you do something again,
like pressing the button again
however, in 2D games, once you start the program
the program keeps running and doesn't stop
until most likely you close the game or you do something special
so imagine, when you play games like
Super Mario or Minecraft or Call of Duty
or any other action oriented games
you can move your character on the screen
and other characters such as monsters or NPCs are also moving on the screen
but how can this happen?
its mechanics is basically the same with hand drawn animation
the character is actually a series of static pictures
but since it updates the pictures really quickly,
it looks like the character is moving
it's the same in video games
so if the game's FPS is 60
which means it updates the screen 60 times per second
so your character looks like moving
but it's actually a series of 60 static images
so to do this animation in our game
we need to create a time in our game
we need to start this game clock
and to do that we will use a class called Thread
and I will name this gameThread
Thread is something you can start and stop
and once a thread started, it keeps your program running until you stop it
it's not like thread itself does something special
but when you want to repeat some process again and again
such as drawing screen 60 times every one second, thread is very useful
so we're gonna use this thread in this GamePanel and to run a thread
we need to implement Runnable to this class
that's the key to use this thread
and we are seeing an error
it's suggesting to add unimplemented methods
so let's do this
then it automatically generates this run method
so what this run method is
probably you can see this explanation
it says,
"when an object implementing interface Runnable (in this case our GamePanel)
is used to create a thread"
"starting the thread causes the object's run method to be called
in that separatory execution thread"
so basically when we start this gameThread
it automatically calls this run method
that's how it works
okay so I'm gonna create a new method here
and here
so we're gonna instantiate this gameThread
and we're gonna pass "this" to this thread constructor
so "this" means this class, so GamePanel
so basically we are passing GamePanel class to this thread's constructor
that's how you instantiate a thread
let's start this thread
it's gonna automatically call this run method
and in this run method, we will create a game loop
which will be the core of our game
[Music]