hi guys this is rice know
last time we implemented npg dials
so now we can talk to them
and we also implemented font files
and
instantiated them in our program so the
correct fonts will be used even after
exporting our game as a jar file
at the end of the last video i said we
were going to implement player life and
event class
but sorry there was a slight change of
runs
apparently some of you guys are tackling
the
known gameplay screen such as title
screen or character creation screen
and wondering how to implement them
so
in this video we will create a title
screen
and nothing fancy it's a really simple
title screen
but anyway let's start
first we create a new game state
so
public final hint
title state
and i'm gonna use zero
and then
we edit
this paint component a little bit
so since we don't need to draw
this background tiles or
npcs or other entities on the title
screen so we add some conditions and
specify what to draw and what not
title
screen
if
game state
equal
title state
and for now
others
so
else
and we're gonna move
everything
pairs
into this l sprocket
also let's change the default game state
to this one
to the
title state
so it starts from this state
okay let's check
so nothing shows up
since you know
we have bypassed old drawings
so we can still hear the music though
and
i don't want to play this music in this
title screen so
yeah let's disable this for now
okay then let's draw this
title screen
in this title state we only call
ui
draw method
but then go to this
ui class
and okay
so here at another
condition
title
state
so gp.game state
all gp dot title
to
state
and like others
we call a method so draw
title screen
or something
and we're gonna create this method
so
yeah maybe here
public void
draw title screen
okay then first let's display the game
title around here
the title name
and i want to use
kind of large font so
let's change the font size
select font
and also use bold
and then
string
text
equal
the game title
game title is
blue boy
adventure
and then we gonna set x and y
and x is
so
we have created
this method before so we can use this
so we can get the x
with
equal
text
and why is
something like uh
yeah plus
three tiles or something
gp dot tile size
time three
and now we
set the color
color
white
and the draw
string string
text and x on the y
okay let's check
yeah like this
i'm using the current black background
color
but if you want to set a different color
then
you can do that by typing like this
so for set color
any color is fine like yeah you can use
rgb number like
ad or something
and then
draw
rectangle or
fill rectangle
and x 0 y 0 and
screen with
screen height
like this
then
yeah
you know you can change the background
color like this
so we have displayed this title name but
this looks kind of generic so now
we're gonna add a little shadow to this
text
so this
is main color
and so before drawing this main text
shadow
so we first we set color shadow color
so let's use black
and then
we draw the same text
text x1 x and y
but the slide three move
to the right hand to the bottom
like plus five and plus five
okay let's check
yep
like this
so now the text has a shadow and it
looks a bit more
i don't know how to say 3d i guess
but i actually like the original black
background color better than this so
i'm gonna change
to
black
and change this shadow color
to gray
yeah like this
very simple but i like it
okay now let's display an image
so i want to display the
player blue boy image around here
a blue boy
image
so first x is
so somewhere in the middle so
for now
and let's divide this screen width
by two
and y is y
plus
two tiles or something
so we add two tiles from this y so from
text y
and then we're gonna draw image so g2
dot draw
image
and the image is
gp.player dot
down one
and okay
x is x
y and which is
g p dot
tiles
size times
so
96 pixels please
tie the size
times 2
or something
yeah let's check
and we want to adjust the position a
little bit so
a little to the left
so since we are displaying
the character with this size so so this
is the center point
so
we're going to subtract
so this sprite size
divide it by two
so this should place the character at
the center
okay
yeah so basically you can type any
number here like
100 or 200 or any number but
i'd recommend you to choose a number
that can be divided by the
original tile size which is 16
16 pixels so otherwise sometimes
the
sprite becomes kind of a distorted and
look a bit ugly so
okay now let's display some
menu
so around here
and first let's change the font size
yeah like a half size
a
new game
and x is this one so we can copy this
x
and y
so we're gonna add
one two three
maybe four tiles
from this image
so gp dot tyres size
times
four and then
draw string
g2
text x and y
and ok let's copy this and
paste
the paste
and the second option is
load
game
and the third one is squid
so let's change this to
one tile and one tile
yup something like this
okay
ah
maybe a bit higher
maybe
3.5
okay and now we want to select
one of these options
all right first we create an integer
public hint
command
number command num
and the default is zero
and then
after drawing this new game
we add the if statement
and check the current command number
and so if the current command number is
zero
then we draw
kind of like a
castle
on the left side of this text so
somewhere around here
so in the case so x minus gp dot type
size or something like that
and we can use the same y
and so if we want to use um like a image
icon instead of this
then uh
yeah you can use a draw image instead of
this drawstring
here let's check
yeah so like
this so now let's add this if statement
to this load game and uh create two
and we're gonna change this command num
one and the two
and now we edit the key handler so we
can change this command num by pressing
a key
so yeah open key handler
and first we
at an if statement i think
title
state
if
dp dot
game state
equal gp dot title state
then
we add some key input and this time we
use
w key and s key
to
move up and move down the castle
so
let's follow copy this
and okay so
if we press w then
we call this command num
and we decrease this command the num
and if you press s key then castle
should go down so
we increase
this command num
yeah like this okay let's check
all right so if you press s key
yeah like this and if you press w key
like this
but
yeah now we can move this castle but the
castle disappears when we hit w
at new game or hit s
ad quit because command num keeps
increasing or decreasing
so
we want to change it so when we hit
s key at this quit then the castle loop
back to this new game so
here we add if statement and
ui dot command
num if command num is less than zero
then
copy
and this time
so
larger than two
then
comma the num is zero
like this
yeah so now the castle is like
looping
like this
all right so now let's add enter key
input so we can execute these options
and for now we'll take care of this new
game and this script
since you know we haven't implemented
save and load function yet so
we'll leave this for now
so we're gonna add another key input
called
key event dot vk
enter
and here first we check the current
command num
so we can use switch or
if statement
a
pui dot
command num if command num is zero
then that means we are selecting
new game so
games so we gonna change
the game state to
playstate
and also we can start the music i think
so
play music
and then
that command
equal one so which means uh
load the game so yeah
add later
and finally
quit option
so if user select this option then we
we're gonna
exit
this program so exit
let's check
all right okay first let's select to
this quit
press enter
oops
why
doesn't work
ah not three why i
i don't know why i put three it's two
all right
quit
yeah so we can finish the program
and if you
choose new game press enter so game
starts
alright so that's basically it
and from here it's a little extra
section so you can skip this if you are
not interested
but anyways maybe some of you guys want
to add a bit more stuff such as a
character making screen or displaying
basic control or
story summary or something like that
so i will create a
bare bones mock-up character class
selection screen
so it's just for demonstration and has
no actual function
but
i hope you get some ideas for your own
project
so basically you can add another
game state such as
character creation state or
story
summary state or something like that but
then we will likely end up creating tons
of game states
and uh personally i want to avoid that
so
instead we create kind of a sub state in
this uh
title state
so in this ui class
okay we're gonna create
integer and
i'm gonna name this
title
scrolling state
and
type zero
so
this time
i'm going to use this number as like for
example i can
state 0 is
the first
screen
and the state 1 is
the second screen or something like that
all right then let's go to this uh
journal title screen
and the first we check the
title screen state
so title
screen state so equal zero
then
we draw this uh you know new game load
game screen
like this
and then
we gonna
create another
condition
if title screen state
call one
and okay so
this keyhander are two
so the inside of this title stative
statement first we check the substate
the current substate
gp dot ui dot
title screen state
and okay so
move everything inside
so we edit this a little bit so if we
select this
new game
then uh
instead of starting the game but
we gonna change the
title screen state
to one
so we can move on to the
character class selection screen
so
here we can draw the screen
dot
set color
dot white
and
font size
selection
schooling
and okay string
text
and select
your class
and
x equal
get x4
centered
text
y
time three or something
and the draw
string
text and x on the y
okay and then next text is
text
we call
fighter
and okay x we can copy this
and y
plus
beta tile size
times three
and copy
and paste
and also
yeah
let's display the castle so if
command
num
equal
zero
then
g2 dot draw structuring
and ok x
minus gp dot type site
all right let's copy this and okay
so fighter
thief
and uh
so salah
and finally
okay
buck or
cancel and okay fine
command number one
two
three so this time we have four options
and okay
so change this to one tile one tile and
maybe this is two tiles
now take care of the key hundred
so
i don't know maybe we can copy this
and paste
it here
so this time we're gonna check
title screen state is one
then
yeah wbs basically it works the same but
uh this time we have four options so
we change this number to three
and we're gonna add one more
num so three
and okay
and yeah okay
so this
command num0 is selecting a fight across
yeah you can probably add some fighter
specific stats
so
do some
specific
and so this
one
so this is safe
and
sorcerer
and then
and if you want to start the game here
then uh
change the game state
to
play state
or if you want to add more stuff then
you can create another
sub state and
yeah do whatever you want
and for this fourth option this is a
back button so
if user select this option then uh
we're gonna change this uh
title
screen state to zero
so we can go back to the
previous screen
okay that's it i guess so let's check
all right
and the first choose this new game
oops what the freak
sorry
apparently
wait a minute
enter
okay
oh
else
and also
this is not necessary now right
okay
entire yes okay select your class
it's a very primitive
character class selection screen
and if you press back
yeah
so we can go back
yeah so you can choose whatever class
you want
like save
so yeah do some save specific stuff
okay
so we have created a mock-up class
selection screen
so that's basically it
that's how you create a title screen
thanks for watching and until next time
[Music]