hi guys this is roy snow last time we
implemented gamestate so we can pause
the game now
and in this video we will create an npc
and implement it into the game so let's
start okay so first
inside of this rest folder
create another package
and name this npc
[Music]
and i have created this old man sprites
with biscuit
so
like the player sprite this also has
8 variations
so you can use these images or you can
prepare your own sprites
so let's copy this image
to this npc package
and before creating this npc we'll do a
little housekeeping so this is kind of a
preparation for creating npc class
in this entity class
we create a constructor
a public
entity
and we get
game panel
gp
desktop gp
equal gp
and okay
game
panel
gp
because we want to use this game panel
in this entity class this time
okay so now we are seeing this error
the fix is pretty simple so we just need
to pass this game panel
to
this entity's constructor
so
super
gp
then the error disappeared
so this means we are calling the
constructor
of the superclass of this class
and passing this gp
and so this entity
is so called abstract class
meaning this class has no instance
so we always instantiate this as a
player class or on npg class or monster
class so we don't instantiate entity
as entity
since entity is just a blueprint for
these character classes
so
if we don't pass gp when we instantiate
a class
the entity cannot receive
this gp
so that's why this line is necessary to
make this code work
so now entity class also has game panel
we can delete this game panel in player
class
and also this one
and yeah we don't need this anymore
okay so that's all for the housekeeping
so let's create an npc class
okay
inside of this entity package
we create a class and i'm gonna name
this
npc
old man
all right
and so this class extends
entity
and the constructor
public
npc
old mem
game panel gp
here as well so we need to pass this gp
to
to the entity class
and okay so first we set direction
down
and also speed
since he's an old man so he moves a bit
slower so
i'm gonna set one
we can also set the
solid area
uh
if you don't need to set it individually
then you can set it in
this entity class so all the characters
can share
so it's like this solid area equal new
rectangle
and so x 0
y 0
so this is the default solid area for
all entity
and if we want to override it then
yeah you can set value here
like this player graph
okay next we import these images
and for the images we we can basically
copy
uh
these methods from playerclass
so like
copy and uh paste here
yeah so this works fine basically but
uh i don't know i think
this feels like kind of redundant so we
are doing almost the same thing in both
player class and uh
this
old main class
so yeah i think
i'm gonna move
this setup
to this entity class
the problem is this
package pass
so
i think so we can delete this
on the instead we include the package
path
when we send this string like this
player
yeah so delete this from this player
class 2 and
add this
package path
and that's so here okay
we don't need this
so for this old man
package passes and pc
and uh okay
so all the main
so since we don't have this setup method
in this subclass anymore so this
automatically calls a method in this
superclass
yeah
yeah this is not the image name but the
image
path
sounds more
accurate
after all
i apologize for the confusion sometimes
you find a way which works better than
you initially planned but that's part of
programming i think
and so this way we don't need to create
that setup method every time we create a
new character class
okay so back in this old man class and
okay so let's change this name this is
not player so uh
just get image i think
and i call it from here
get image
yeah this is okay for now so
now go to game panel
just like we did for object
we create an npc array
so public
entity
and pc
equal new
entity
and 10 i think then go to
this asset setup
and
create a method
public
void
set npc
and here we instantiate the
old man
gp.10 pc
equal new
and pc
all the mem
and i think we're gonna pass gp
yeah
okay and we're gonna set
his position
world x
i wanna place him
kinda close to the starting point so
i'm gonna
sit
so call 21
and
law is also 21.
okay
and now inside of this game panel
we call the method
okay somewhere around here
dot set any pc
all right then
so inside of this paint component
so we draw any pc
so
probably after this object
npc
and for
int
i equal 0
i
list some any pc dot length
i prosperous
and if npc
i
not equal normal
then we gonna draw
sony pc
dot draw
g2
dot
this
yeah but yeah
we haven't created this draw method so
we need to create a draw method
and just like we did for object
we create a draw method
not in
this old man graph but
in the entity class
public void draw
we get graphics
2d
g2
and what we do here is kind of similar
to
a
very super object
so first we can
copy
this
and uh
paste here
but the difference is
unlike object any pc can move around and
has several sprite variations
so we need to switch the sprite
depending on its direction
so for this we can copy the lines from a
player class
and play a draw so we just
copy this switch statement
so this
direction
choosing switch statement so copy this
and paste
inside of this if statement
and also
copy this one this line too
and paste here
okay
so the basic system is
pretty much identical to
the object so we find out its screen x
and the y
based on the player's position
and if it's in the
camera frame
then we draw it
yeah let's check this
oops
hello
what is this
draw npc draw
ah okay i think we don't need to pass
this game panel anymore because
this entity class already has game
panels so yeah
let's delete this
yep okay
let's check this
okay
yeah so now
the
npc appeared on the screen
but of course
he's not moving
so
let's move him
inside of this entity we create two
methods
the first one is
public
void
set
action and the other one is public void
update
and uh okay
inside of this old main class
we create uh
public void set
action
method here too
in this set action we set the
character's behavior
so
this kind of work as it's ai
and we want to set a different behavior
to each character so that's why we
created this method in this subclass
tool so we can override it
and uh
for update
basically it works identical in all npcs
so
we don't need to create this
this update
here we can just share the one in the
entity class
you know so if there is no update method
here then the program automatically
refer to the one in its super class
this might feel a bit complicated at
first but
once you get used to how this
inheritance works in java it's actually
a pretty convenient
yeah anyways let's set the
behavior of this character okay first
london
london equal new
and
in high i decor random dot
next int
plus one
so we use this random class and this
means
we get a random number from 1 to
i added one because otherwise it peaks
from
0 to 99
and
i kind of like you know 1 to 100 better
so that's why
so this basically uh
pick up a number
or
from 1 to
and then if statement if
i
call
equal or less than 25
then
direction
is
up
if
i
get 25
and
then
direction
called down
if
i
larger than 50
and
direction
recall
right no
left
and if
larger than 75
and
e4 or less than 100
then
direction
is
right
so this is like a
simplest ai ever
25 percent of the time it goes up 25
percent of the time it goes down and so
on
uh yeah so this is okay for now so
let's take care of this
update method
all right first we call
that set action
you might think but you know this set
action is empty
yeah but
we created this in this
old main class 2 and if the subclass has
the same method it takes a priority
and so as i said before this will be
used by all the npcs
and the code is pretty similar to
this player's update
but a bit simpler
okay
first question
home equal
false
and then we're going to check
collision
dot
check tile
and entities
this
so it's going to pass
this class
as an entity
and
for the movement i think we can just
copy and paste from the player graph
so we can
copy this
so this collision on if statement and
also this sprite counter
so
we copy this
and paste here
and okay that's it i think
all right and then
go to game panel
and inside of this update method so
we're gonna
update any pc2
layer
and pc
so another for loop
i
sign in pc dot links
i press plus
and if npc
hi
not equal
no
then we're gonna update
this npc
yeah like this i think
it's okay now so let's check this
oh
yeah
the heat
the envy is moving but it looks
terribly long
and yeah we can fix this
so what is happening here is the npc is
changing its direction you know rapidly
because right now in every frame there
is a chance to change the direction
so it would be better to set some kind
of an interval
all right
in this entity class
we're gonna create an
integer
power
public
int
i'm gonna name this
action
lock
counter or something
and go to this old man class
every time this set action gets called
we add this counter
press plus
okay and here we're gonna create if
statement
action
look counter
equal
or something
then
we're gonna pick a
direction
and uh
after that we reset the counter
so this way once it picked up a
direction
it won't change for the next
120 frames
which means two seconds
so yeah you can
adjust this number as you like alright
so let's check this again
yep
so now the npc is moving more
naturally
and
uh okay tile collision is i think tile
collision is also happening
let me see
come on
hit the tile hit the tile yeah yeah i
think uh the tile collision is also
working properly
but still you know
no collision with players so let's
implement it as well
so let's open this collision checker
and okay
inside we're gonna create another
method
public
int
name this check
entity
and
we're gonna get
entity
and
also another entity
and this is
allay and this is target
and we're gonna use this method to check
npc
or
monster collision
and the
npc collision works almost identical to
this
object
so i think we can
copy this
and
paste it here
and we're gonna change this
object to
this target
target.links
and here target
target
and
this and also
this and
this
and this
that's everything maybe
and also this time we don't need to
check targets
collision
since you know
unlike object
or any pcs or monsters are solid
so
we can just delete this
and we don't need to check if entity is
player
so we can delete these two
like this
hey
okay
these and uh delete these
yeah like this
so
this return
the index of the
collided npc
if collision didn't happen it returns
so now go to
display graph
and check the npc collision
check
npc call region
so hint and pc
index
equal gp dot g
check card
check
entity
and so this time first we pass this
player and then target
is
this npc
so we're gonna pass this npc array
as this target
so you know this can scan
this array and check if
any of these npcs are colliding with
player
then
result of the collision
we can type it here but i think it would
be better to handle it in
different method like this one
so
like in
interact
npc
and pc
index
so we're gonna create this method
uh okay somewhere around here
void
interacting pc
yeah get the index
copy this if statement and okay
uh
for now let's display some text
so
you are
hitting
an npc or something
yeah
okay i think so yeah let's check this
all right
console
okay
yeah
yeah collision is happening
but yeah
did you see see it yeah
like this
so now any pc collision is happening but
only when player
hit an npc
so let's implement the opposite tool so
any pc to player
so this collision checker game
and now we're gonna create another
method a public
void
check
player
and
ntt
entity
so this time we don't need to return the
index
so the method is void
and i think we can basically copy and
paste from this
check entity
method
the only difference is
we don't need to scan the array
so we can ignore that part
so
yeah i think we can just copy
wait
inside of this
if statement so
this one i
think copy
and paste
and this time change this target
to
player
gp.player
okay
yeah and uh yeah we don't need this
index
like this
yeah okay i think
all right so this should work so let's
check it
okay so come on hit me
come on hit me
come on
oh no of course
ah sorry
we're not checking the collision so
inside of this entity
and update so
after this checking tile ah okay and uh
i forgot another thing
yeah let's check object two
so
like
you know if there is a door then uh
collision should happen so
check
object
and object is uh yeah
so this and uh
so this is not player so
the boolean is false
and okay so and so let's check
player collision two
and yeah past this entity
okay so now this should work so let's
check
okay come on hit me
okay
yeah so he stopped it
yeah so now
collision is happening
from
both direction
player to npc and then pc to player
yeah
perfect
alright so i think that's it for now and
next time we will implement a dialog
system so
we can talk to him
thanks for watching and until next time
[Music]
you