hi guys this is rice no
last time we created the event handler
class so now we can trigger event
when player character
hits a certain tile
however after uploading the video i
received this comment from
terminallyunique95 so
the player character keep receiving
damage
if you keep pushing him in the same
direction and yes i was aware of this
and i thought it's somehow acceptable
since you can
avoid getting further damage if you
change your direction
and i knew handling this would require a
little reconstruction of the code so i
was kind of being lazy and took an easy
way but i have to agree it would be
definitely better if the system is more
flexible and give us more options so
thank you for pointing this out and
giving me a push to work on it
we still reuse the majority of the code
that we have written in the last video
and i think you will like the result
anyway let's start
okay so last time we used this rectangle
class to create the event select
but this time we create a new class for
this
so
inside of this main package
create a class
i'm going to name this
event
left
and this class
extends
rectangle
so this is basically an extended version
of
rectangle
it still has all the functions of
rectangle but we can add more
and first we create the default x and y
variables here
and select
default x and event
select default y
right
then we create a boolean
event
dom
call first
so
with this boolean we can check if this
event has already happened or
never happened yet
so this gives us an option to create on
one time only event
then go to this
event handler class
and remove this rectangle event left and
also this integers
and instead we use this event left
and select
as a two dimensional array
and now inside of this constructor
we instantiate this
select
equal new
event
left
and the size is b dot
max
fold call and gp dot
all love
so now we have an event rectangle on
every single tile on the map
basically
and then we're gonna set the
this solid area
to this alley
into call
equals zero
into now
zero
and y
call
system
max
world call
and
lao is listen peter
max
world law
and we're gonna
copy this
or cut on the paste here
and change this to
event rate call and
so
after this this is this
and also
this
call
law
love
and okay this is not a rectangle but
event
left
okay so now all these event elect has
this uh kind of a solid area
and now update
this heat method
so here's where we're gonna add
this
call
and the law
okay so event call so
let's change this
color on the law
because it's shorter
so
yeah we're going to add this corondell
to this one and this one and this one
and this is
called and
law
and this is also
even direct
around the law
and this is also
and okay
yeah
okay this is it i think
so all the error is gone now
okay let's check
what
oh no
of course
stop it
yeah sorry i i forgot to
add call here so this loop doesn't end
so uh yeah let's set this if call we
call
that max
or call
then a
call call zero and low
prosperous
so this should end and the loop
let's check
okay
and okay so fit yeah
okay so it is working just like before
and now let's utilize the flexibility
that we acquired by creating this
event direct alley
so for example maybe you want to make
this
you know damage bit event one time only
so once you fell into the pit and
receive damage then
you can work on the tile after that
so
i will show you how to implement such
event
okay first
we add parameters
to these event methods
so
call and
log
and also
yeah here too so
27 we pass
the
call and allow data to this event method
2.
so this way we can access to a specific
event
and
after handling this event
we can call that
event dom boolean
event
left
call
and allow
dot event
done
call true
then
inside of this hit method we had one
more condition here
event
left
call
and allow
dot
event done
equal
false
so this way the event only happens when
the
event down boolean is false so let's
check
all right let's fall into the pit
okay fall into a pit
and now
yeah so the event won't happen again
so this damage bit event is one time
only now
yeah so this is one way to utilize this
event left class
okay then another case
so this time
the damage pit is not one time only
whenever you step on the tile you
receive damage
yeah so let's disable this for now
but we don't want it to happen
repeatedly like before
like this
okay first we create variables
integer
previous
event
x and
previous
event y
and also bull bullion
can touch
event
equal true
what we gonna do is we set some kind of
margin and make it so if an event
happened it won't happen again
until player character
move away from the event rectangle by
one tile distance
so this way we can prevent the event
from happening repeatedly
so
after player character
hit an event
we record his word x and worldwide
previous
event x
equal g p dot player dot
old x
yes event y equal gp dot play
yeah dot
worldwide
and
based on
this information we check the distance
between player character and the last
event
check if the player
character
is more than one tile
away from the last event
okay uh
let me type first
i think x
distance
call
mass dot abs
gp.player dot word
x
minus
previous
event
x
and y
distance
equal
dot abs
gp dot
here dot world y
minus
previous
event y
then er distance
equal
mass dot max
x
distance
and y distance
and if
this turns it's
larger than gp dot
tile size
then
can
touch
event
equal true
so in case you are not familiar with
these
mass
methods
this mass abs returns absolute values of
this
this calculation
so which means even if the number is
negative it still gets it as a positive
number so
this is useful when you want to know the
pure distance between objects
then we use this must.max
so this simply picks a greater number of
two integers
so either it's horizontal or vertical
we take a greater one
and if this distance is greater than the
tile size then it means player character
is more than one tile away from the last
event so
we can trigger
the event again
and we add if statement here
if
can touch event equal
true
then we can check
this
event
and also
after this damage pit event
we add this line
can
touch
event
equal
parts
and to test this i'm gonna add one more
damage bit
at
somewhere around here
core 13 and
low
and this time i'm gonna set
any to this required direction
yeah so direction doesn't matter
okay let's check
okay
here four interpret
but now it doesn't happen repeatedly
like before and this one as well
going to pit
yeah
but you can still move move away
like this
where is it this bit here
yeah yeah so now once the event happens
it won't happen again until player
character takes one tile distance from
it
for this healing event
we don't need to move away to
trigger the game since we
we didn't add
this drawing to this
healing pool method
but you can choose how you handle it
yup that's it
so the event system is more flexible and
customizable now
and we can add
more element
to this event select class whenever we
get a new idea
i should have done this in the first
place so i apologize for making the
process a bit redundant
i hope you like this new system
and in the next video i will answer
another comment
and address a
couple bugs regarding npc introduction
and then we move on to the next stuff
thanks for watching and until next time
[Music]