last time we loaded the character sprites
and implemented a simple animation system
so we can control our player character
now let's draw some background tiles
by the way, we don't need these variables anymore
since we took care of the player movement in Player class
so you can delete this
so first we need some background tile images
so i prepared three tiles
we will add more tiles later
but for now three tiles should be enough
so inside of this resource package
let's create another package
i'm gonna name this "tiles"
and we're gonna copy these tile images
to the tiles package
and then from this source folder
we're gonna create another package
and inside of this tile package,
create a class called Tile
and this is a class which represents a single tile
and for now we add two elements
the one is...
and the other one is...
so this class is okay for now
now let's create another class
inside of this tile package
i'm gonna name this TileManager
in this class, first we're gonna use GamePanel
and also this Tile class
we create this Tile as an alley and name this "tile"
import GamePanel
then let's create a constructor
and we're gonna get GamePanel as "gp"
also we're gonna set the size of this Tile array
i'm gonna choose 10 for now
this means we're going to create 10 kinds of tiles
so like a glass tile, a water tile, a wall tile...
if we need more then we can always change
this number to like 15 or 20
but i think 10 is enough
then create a method
and we're gonna call this method
from this constructor
kind of similar to the Player class
so we're gonna load these tile images
in this getTileImage method
so again, try and catch
and here so we're gonna instantiate
this Tile array
and then type a file path
so the file path will be...
since these are inside of this tiles package so...
so we created this BufferedImage inside of this Tile class
we're gonna put this tile file image into this BufferedImage
let's copy this and paste
and the tile[1] will be wall
and the tile[2] will be water
instantiation is done and
we create a draw method
inside of this TileManager too
import
so let's draw a tile for testing
so to draw a tile, type like this
so first a BufferedImage
so let's draw this grass tile
and then x and y, so 0 and 0
and width and height, so gp.tileSize and gp.tileSize
and the ImageObserver is null
and now let's go to this GamePanel class
instantiate this TileManager
and pass this GamePanel class
then inside of this paintComponent we're gonna type...
so we're gonna call this draw method
inside of the TileManager
and make sure to type this line before this "player.draw(g2)"
so it's like a layer
in this case we draw tiles first, then player
if it's opposite, background tiles will hide the player character
so we cannot see the player character
so make sure to draw tiles before player
let's check this
yeah okay
so our first tile is displayed
so let's draw some more tiles
so go back to this TileManager class
let's copy this and paste it
draw a wall tile and a water tile
but we have to change this x and y otherwise it's just overwrite
so let's add a tile size to x
and add tile size again so 48 plus 48 will be 96
okay let's check this
alright. so we have drawn a grass tile, a wall tile, and a water tile
like this, we can draw tiles on the screen
so let's check this
alright
i just created 5 tiles horizontally, 5 tiles vertically
that's what i typed
but obviously this is not the efficient way of typing or drawing
it's just too much typing
so we need more efficient tile drawing system
so let's not do this
instead, we will create a while loop
and kind of automate the process so we can avoid a lot of typing
first create some variables
then create a while loop
so this loop continues if col is smaller than gp.max...
oh okay
ah sorry
we need to change these variables to "public"
and also this integer row is smaller than...
so inside of this loop we're gonna draw tiles
so for now let's draw a grass tile
these are variables
okay
first, col is 0 and row is 0
and x is 0 and y is 0
basically this is 0:0
so it's gonna draw a tile at 0:0
here
after that we're gonna increase this col by 1
and then we're going to increase this x
so we increase this col one by one
and if this hits this maxScreenCol which is 16
then we're gonna reset this col and also reset this x
and then increase this row by 1
and also increase this y position
okay i think. let's check this
so we have succeeded to place tiles on the whole screen
but we are only using the grass tile
so to render an actual map, we create a map data first
then let this loop read the data
and to store this map data we use a text file
it's a simple method but also pretty popular
and effective method as well
so first open this notepad
and then we're gonna type...
and we're gonna copy this
and paste 11 times
so a single line has 16 zeros and it has 12 lines
and each number represents a tile
so this is a 16x12 tile map which is the same size as our screen
and this 0 means tile number so it's a grass tile
so if you want to place a wall tile
you just need to change this to 1
and if we want to place a water tile,
change the number to 2
let me create a sample map real quick
something like this
now let's save the file
i'm gonna name this just "map01.txt"
then inside of this res folder,
create another package
i'm going to name this "maps"
where's the file?
okay so we're gonna copy this map file
to this "maps" folder
so we got this map data file
so let's load this data
first, create a variable
and this is going to be an array
and inside of this constructor
we're gonna instantiate this mapTileNum
and the size is...
so basically we're gonna put all these numbers
to this mapTileNum array
so to do that,
we're gonna create another method
so another try and catch
this time just "Exception e"
we're gonna use this InputStream class
and here we're gonna type the file path
of this text file
and import this InputStream
import this
and also this
so we used this InputStream
to import this text file
and we're gonna use this BufferedReader
to read the content of this text file
it's just a format to read this text file
and after this, again we're going to create an integer "col"
start from 0 and integer row, start from 0
and while loop again
so smaller than maxScreenColl
and also row is smaller than gp.maxScreenRow
inside of this while loop
we're gonna read this text file
and maxScreenCol or maxScreenRow is the limit of this loop
because it has no data beyond that boundary
so this BufferedReader can read text files
and this readLine means it's gonna read a single line
and put it into this String "line"
and once we read the line, we enter another while loop
and double quotations and a space
so what we are doing here is,
from the line we just read,
we're gonna get these numbers one by one
and put them into this alley
and then we're gonna create this integer variable
and name this "num"
and the index is "col"
so basically we are changing this from String to Integer
this readLine only get the data as String
and we split this line and this is also String
so we need to change this from String to Integer
so we can use them as a number
then we're gonna use this mapTileNum integer
the index is col and row
after this we're gonna increase this col by 1
and then if this col hits the maxScreenCol
finally we're gonna close this BufferedReader
because we're not gonna use this
so basically we're gonna scan this text file
line by line so
first this line and divide it to each number
and get them to the mapTileNum
and once finish this line then
go to the next line and the next... until this loop is over
so now we should be able to load this map data
so let's draw the loaded map data
we just need to arrange this while loop a little bit
instead of this fixed image, first we delete this
and also i think we're gonna create an integer
so again we start from 0
we're gonna extract a number from this mapTileNum
and get this as a tile number
then we're gonna draw an image
so this is gonna work as an index of this Tile array
so if we get the number 0 from this
it's gonna draw a grass tile
and if we get 1 from this alley then
it's gonna draw a wall tile
if it was 2 then it's gonna draw a water tile
so everything is stored inside of this mapTileNum array
now this should be okay so let's check this
oops
why
ah
okay we didn't call this load map method
this should be okay
let's check
alright
so we succeeded to draw a map file
looks nice i think
also i just remembered one more thing
yeah this is just fine but...
probably it would be better if we just pass a String here
we're gonna pass this path information from here
and get it as a String
and put it here
because maybe you will create a different map later
so map02, map03 map04...
and whenever you want to load a different map
you just need to call this loadMap and type the file path here
so you don't have to create another loadMap method
anyway we have succeeded to load our map file
and draw the tiles on the screen
but still it's a small map
it's only as large as a single screen
so next time we will create a world map
that we will actually use it in our game
and implement a game camera so the background tiles change
according to the player character's movement
thanks for watching and until next time
[Music]