and now let's talk about the font in game
so if you like the current Arial font,
you can skip this part
but maybe you think
this Arial font looks a bit too generic
maybe you want to test a different font
and see how it looks
you can change the font by changing the name here
but it's not like you can type anything
the font needs to be in your computer
in this Windows folder,
you can find this Fonts folder
then you can see the fonts in your computer
for example, I have this Cambria font
so i can change this to Cambria
so it looks like this
but there is a slight problem in this method
since the font is dependent on local environment
so for example, once you finish your development
if you export your game and...
let your friends play it
you never know what fonts are in their computer
so to make sure the correct font will be displayed
we can include the font in our program package
then your desired font will surely be displayed
in any environment
this is what most of the game developers do
when they create a game
including a font file in your program package
which is especially crucial when you localize your game
into other languages
so first thing you need to do is prepare a font file
and i think it needs to be a true type font
if it's true type font, you can use any font
and this time I've prepared two fonts
the one is a pixel font called MaruMonica
this was created by a Japanese creator
and this is so far my favorite pixel font
it's completely free
and you can use it for both personal and commercial purpose
and readability is pretty good for a pixel font
and the other one is this Purisa Bold
so this is just for testing to show how it looks
since this is a pretty unique font
so first, inside of this res folder
create another package
and name this "font"
copy this font file to this package
Purisa Bold and also MaruMonica
then we're gonna import these fonts
I'm gonna delete these Arial
and instead maruMonica and prisaB or something
and I'm going to delete this too
so here we're gonna instantiate the font
and here we input a file pass
let me get the file name
and import InputStream
then
and the font file is "is"... InputStream
and i think we need to surround this
with try and catch
so we need to catch these two exceptions
FontFormatException and IOException
and okay one more font
can i move this inside of this try?
is this okay? Ah okay
then let's import another one too
and copy, yep, okay
so now these two fonts are instantiated
so instead of this arial_40,
let's use this maruMonica
okay let me increase the font size a little bit
so this is how MaruMonica font looks
I like this retro feel a lot
so now let's try Prisa Bold too
i just copy this and...
comment out and purisaB...
this font is much larger than MaruMonica so...
text is bleeding out of the frame again but
anyways as you can see
it gives you a completely different feel
so font is actually pretty important
it sets the atmosphere of your game
I'm gonna use MaruMonica for this game
but you can test any font you like
and please find one you like the best
and also if you don't like the jaggy of this kind of font,
you can set anti-alias on
so when you set the font,
you can add this line
yeah like this let's check
can you see the difference?
and for this MaruMonica
this anti-aliasing doesn't work
i guess that's because this is a pixel
that kinda makes sense I think
yeah anyway that's everything for now
this turned out to be a pretty long video
but now we can talk to NPCs
and in the next video,
i think we will implement player life
and also create an Event class
so we can add some events
so thanks for watching
and until next time
[Music]