hi guys here's another extra video of my 2D game tutorial
although we will edit our code a little bit at the end
the main theme of this video is pixel art
so you can continue tutorial without applying the changes in this video so don't worry
but if you are interested in pixel art or how the game's graphics have changed, please keep watching
if you have been checking the community tab on my channel you might know that i've been working on the pixel art of the game for a while
i kind of like the original look of the game
it's simple, blocky, and very 8-bit
and to be honest, i was never really interested in drawing pixel art
i was more into programming
and also drawing pixel art looked very difficult and require some special skill and talent
but then i stumbled upon youtube channels such as pixel pete or adam she units
these channels provide really good pixel art tutorials
and made me feel maybe i can also improve my tiles a little bit
so they actually picked my interest in drawing pixel art
so first of all i wanna say huge thanks to these channels
i think this didn't happen if i didn't find their channels
so i decided to work on my tiles and i had these six tiles
and first i started working on the grass tile
so instead of putting these random dots
throughout the
tile
so i decided to draw three glasses like
this
yeah something like this
so it looks like this but i felt this
was a
a bit too much
so i also created
this totally blank
all green grass style
and
decided to use this as the main grass
style and
so use this one as kind of an accent
tile so
i changed every grass tile to the blank
green tile and at the
accent tile here and there
so it looked like this
so now we have two graph styles
so blank one and uh accent one
then i worked on the tree tile not much
change but i deleted this
dot
and changed the color and also edited
the shading a little bit
so yeah i'm still not really satisfied
with how this shading looks
but
yeah for now this is how it looks
yeah so like this
then i started working on the water tile
and this was quite a work because
i wanted to
take care of the edge
of these tiles
and for this one pixel pead has made an
amazing water tile tutorial so
i recommend you to check that
so anyway to take care of the edge
nicely we need to create several
patterns first i deleted this
white dot
and also changed the watercolor a little
bit
and then pick the color from the glass
tile
and draw the edge of the land like this
then created the earth part like this
then choose a bit darker color and
create shadow
and then randomize it a little bit
yeah something like this
so then choose a dark green color so
darker than this gray style
and draw the edge of this glass
like this
and uh
to create a bit more smooth transition i
picked a bit lighter green than this
and put it here and there
like
this then pick the watercolor again and
choose a bit darker
this time
to create some shadow
oops
like this
and i also used a bit
lighter color
than this
and
add some accent
accent to here something
like this
a bit darker
something like
this very subtle
yeah
okay so let's expand this image a little
bit so
place this here
okay
and for the opposite bank
so
okay
and for the side bunks
something like this so for the
cyberbunks i included the earth or dart
a little bit
but i think either way is fine i've
noticed some games show ours on the
cyberbunk
and some games don't so just show the
grasses and water
and now create
a tile which connects this top bank and
this cyberpunk
[Music]
okay
then create a tile which connects this
bottom bunk and this side bunk
okay
and then
so you can
flip these images horizontally
like this
and then we create four more tiles
so
so i chose several colors between white
and this watercolor and created a little
gradation
yeah so that's it for the
water tile
so in the end i created uh
variations okay so the next is this sand
tile i was using this sand tile as a
kind of a
you know load
so i decided to make this look more like
a load
so i first i deleted the dot then i
picked a little darker color than this
base color
and created some pattern
dude
and what i did was basically the same as
the water tiles
so i created 11 patterns
so it can handles most of the
situation
and now
as for that tile
and for this one i just i don't know i
didn't i didn't have any good idea so i
just uh you know randomize the pattern
basically
it's like uh really randomly
[Music]
yeah something like this
and finally the wall tile
i decided to keep using this brick
pattern and
make it a bit more detailed
so basically i change the brightness of
this gray color
so
yes something like this
so i used a
gray color and changed the
like a brightness and so created some
shadows and
gradation
and so and kind of london right
randomize it
yeah
so
that's everything i think
i ended up
creating 32 tiles
yeah let's implement these styles and
see how they look like in the game
and first we need to
increase the size of this tile array
you know since we have more than 10
tiles now so like
yeah 50
should be enough for now and
yeah we can always increase the size
whenever we want then we can add new
tiles to like a atari index 678
yeah that's basically it but um i
decided to
not to use this you know index 0 to 9
tiles so
7 8 9
sold
so i just put the
this
blank grass style to
index 0 to 9 as a placeholder
and we're going to start from uh
index 10
and this is also a paragraph style but
this is the actual graph style we're
going to use and
these nine tiles we don't use
but i put this grass style as a
placeholder because otherwise you know
it can get
not point except exception error and i
need to add an extra code to avoid that
and that's a little bit too much pain
and the reason
i wanted to start from
index 10 is pretty simple
right now we are only using single digit
number
to create this world map but uh
if we add two digit numbers too
then it becomes like this
so single digit number and the two digit
numbers are mixed like this then uh
it kind of disturbs the placement of
these numbers
and make it a bit
harder to read or look
so program-wise it still works just fine
no problem
so it's purely
like appearance reason
so
i update new tiles like this
so these are placeholder
so from here so these are the tiles
we're gonna use
yeah and this is the new map file
so every number is two digit like this
and i also changed the map a little bit
so in the old
map the world was surrounded by these
trees so as if we are in uh
like a big forest or something
but i thought it's a bit boring so i
decided to surround the land by water
so now our world became an
island
so yeah okay let's delete
these all old tiles
and copy these new tiles
and also
yeah
now we're gonna use this word world b2
file so let's change the
file path to
word with two
okay so i think everything is ready so
yeah let's take a look
yeah
yeah like this so now
it's surrounded by water
[Music]
so
hmm
yeah i think this looks better
yeah and this is where we
we found a treasure chest
but in the second half we're gonna place
a different thing
looks good
[Music]
so yeah i think everything is placed
correctly
yeah so this is the new look of the game
it took about a week to create those
tiles but uh i think it was worth it
and like before i'm gonna upload this
new tileset on my drive so so if you're
using
my tileset and wants to update to this
new one you can download it and
so i'm going to upload the
new map file too so you can use this
style set
in your environment too
anyway that's uh that's it for now so
thanks for watching and until next time
[Music]